Guide to the Vance Bryant Erickson Photographs
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Vance Bryant Erickson photographs
1920-1925
PC0059
Erickson, Vance Bryant, 1901-
0.25 Linear feet
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Gift of Vance P. Erickson.
Information about Access
None.
BIOGRAPHY
Vance B. Erickson was a member of the Stanford University class of 1924, earning his a.b. in June. He married Alberta Curtner, a member of the class of 1925, in September 1926. Erickson returned to Stanford for graduate work, earning his MA degree in Chemistry in 1940.
SCOPE AND CONTENT
This collection documents Erickson's undergraduate days at Stanford, 1920 through 1924, with a few items dating from 1925. Most of the collection consists of negatives, presumably from photographs taken by Erickson. There are also photoprints and postcards, many of which are Berton Crandall images. Subjects include the Frosh-Soph Tie-Up, Roughs' Day, Big Game bonfires, El Capitan Club, dormitory rooms in Encina Hall, the stadium, the cactus garden, Sand Hill road, and campus views. There are also several images of Palo Alto, including a student rooming house. Students pictured include Everett Bailey, Vance Erickson, Donald Harger, George Harman, Russell Pearson, Burt Procter, William Hyde Irwin, Daniel Gage, William R. Gage, Burton A. Noble, Harold H. Strain, Alberta Curtner, and Paul Wilbur.
Arrangement note
The prints and negatives were kept separate and arranged alphabetically by subject. The negative number with each negative is from Erickson's inventory, now in folder 103.
Access Terms
College students--Photograph collections.; College students--United States--Conduct of life.; Photography.; Student Life--Frosh-Soph Tie Up
Collection Contents
- NEGATIVES
  - Aircraft on campus field, seen from Encina room 527 (neg. 70) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Angel of Grief, (neg. 31), 1921 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Bailey, Everett, (neg. 97), 1924 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Basketball Pavilion (neg. 68) (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Bonfire being built, (neg. 13), 1920 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Bonfire being built, (neg. 15), 1920 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Bonfire being built, (neg. 47), 1921 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Bonfire structure, (neg. 65), 1921 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Bonfire structure, (neg. 86), 1923 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Cactus Garden, (neg. 27), 1921 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Cactus Garden, (neg. 29), 1921 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Cactus Garden, (neg. 19), 1921 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Cactus Garden, (neg. 20), 1921 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Campus view from Encina Hall looking east, (neg. 75), 1923 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Campus view from Toyon Hall (neg. 102) (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Campus viewed from the west (neg. 101) (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Car trouble, (neg. 42), 1921 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Chemistry building, (neg. 30), 1921 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Cyclists, (neg. 12), 1920 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Eating Clubs, with Toyon construction in background, (neg. 74), 1922 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - 327 Emerson Street rooming house, (neg. 9), 1920 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Encina Gym exterior, (neg. 18), 1921 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Encina Hall room 249, (neg. 62) (students: Creed, Procter, Ellis), 1921 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Encina Hall room 351, (neg. 48), 1921 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Encina Hall room 351, view from, (neg. 57), 1921 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Encina Hall room 527 (neg. 71) (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Erickson, Vance, (neg. 95), 1924 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Harger, Donald, (neg. 96), 1924 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Harmon, George, (neg. 85), 1923 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Inner Quad (neg. 25) (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Lagunita, (neg. 17), 1920 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Lagunita, (neg. 99), 1925 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Main Library, (neg. 24), 1921 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Mausoleum, (neg. 28), 1921 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Museum, (neg. 21), 1921 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Palm Drive, (neg. 2), 1920 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Palo Alto, (neg. 32), 1921 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Palo Alto, (neg. 33), 1921 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Palo Alto, (neg. 34), 1921 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Palo Alto, University Circle, (neg. 7), 1920 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Pearson, Russell, (neg. 76), 1923 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Pescadero Beach, (neg. 69), 1923 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Proctor, Burt, (neg. 41), 1921 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Quad, front view, (neg. 3), 1920 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - ROTC building (neg. 73) (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Roughs Day, (neg. 45), 1921 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Roughs Day, (neg. 46), 1921 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Roughs Day, (neg. 49), 1921 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Roughs Day, (neg. 50), 1921 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Roughs Day, (neg. 56), 1921 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Roughs Day, (neg. 55), 1921 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Roughs Day, (neg. 53), 1921 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Roughs Day, (neg. 51), 1921 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Roughs Day, (neg. 64), 1921 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Roughs Day, man in woman's attire, (neg. 52), 1921 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Roughs Day, in Greek costume, (neg. 54), 1921 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Roughs Day, Bill Irwin, (neg. 60), 1921 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Roughs Day, water wagon (neg. 67), 1921 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Roughs Day, (neg. 92) (Silvius, D. Gage, Meyer, Smith, Clark), 1923 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Roughs Day, (neg. 91) (Clark, Silvius, W. Gage, D. Gage), 1923 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Roughs Day, horseshoe game (neg. 90), 1923 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Roughs Day, Daniel Gage (neg. 89), 1923 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Rubble from library destroyed in '06 quake, (neg. 22), 1921 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Sand Hill Road, (neg. 14), 1920 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Santa Cruz beach and boardwalk (neg. 81) (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Santa Cruz boardwalk (neg. 79) (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Santa Cruz pier (neg. 80) (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - S.P. station in Palo Alto, (neg. 6), 1920 (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Stadium, incomplete, (neg. 40), 1921 (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Stadium, (neg. 44), 1921 (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Stadium, stage for opera, (neg. 66), 1921 (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - Street on campus ?, (neg. 26), 1921 (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - Student (Clark) after Tie-Up, (neg. 39), 1921 (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - Student, frosh (neg. 10) (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - Student, frosh, in checkered Ford, (neg. 11), 1920 (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - Student, frosh, wearing dink, (neg. 8), 1920 (Box 1, Folder 76)
  - Student in room, Thanksgiving Day feast, (neg. 16), 1920 (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - Student with handgun and target, (neg. 37), 1921 (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - Students: Hitchcock, Harger, Noble (neg. 78) (Box 1, Folder 79)
  - Students: Moore, Pearson, Kylberg (neg. 77) (Box 1, Folder 80)
  - Students, Horner, Somers, Berk (neg. 43), 1921: (Box 1, Folder 81)
  - Students, (neg. 87) Sloan's chemistry class en route to Spreckels Plant in Salinas, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 82)
  - Students, H. Strain and C. Benedict (neg. 88) part of Sloan's class trip, 1923: (Box 1, Folder 83)
  - Students, Alberta Curtner, Vance Erickson, M. Curtner in Santa Cruz (neg. 93), 1924: (Box 1, Folder 84)
  - Students in cap and gown, D. Harger, J. Wright, B. Noble (neg. 98), 1925: (Box 1, Folder 85)
  - Students, Wilbur Bailey, Bernice Chase, Alberta Curtner in Half Moon Bay (neg. 100), 1925: (Box 1, Folder 86)
  - Students after baseball fight (neg. 63) (Box 1, Folder 87)
  - Students after Tie-Up, (neg. 38), 1921 (Box 1, Folder 88)
  - Students on Emerson Street, (neg. 35), 1921 (Box 1, Folder 89)
  - Study table, (neg. 36), 1921 (Box 1, Folder 90)
  - Toyon Hall from Encina (neg. 72) (Box 1, Folder 91)
  - Wilbur, Paul, 1924 (neg. 94) (Box 1, Folder 92)
- PHOTOGRAPHS AND POSTCARDS
  - Big Game at Berkeley, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 93)
  - Baseball fight, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 94)
  - Bonfires (Box 1, Folder 95)
  - El Capitan Club, 1922, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 96)
  - Encina Club, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 97)
  - Frosh-Soph Tie-Up, 1920, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 98)
  - Pajamareno, group shot, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 99)
  - Water fight, 1920, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 100)
  - Posters (from Tie-Ups and baseball fight) (Box 1, Folder 101)
  - Roughs Day, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 102)
  - Erickson's inventory for these photographs and negatives, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 103)